<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adrian Juarez</title>
    <description>Adrian Juarez&#39;s Website and Blog</description>
    <link>http://www.aejuarez.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aejuarez.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Don&#39;t Pass Up Password Managers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/CombinationLock.png&quot; alt=&quot;Combination Lock&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You use the same password for everything, right? Or, maybe you let Google Chrome remember all your passwords. If this at all describes your password habits, you&amp;rsquo;re vulnerable for some serious violations in privacy and security. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two reasons why you might be a redneck using bad passwords:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1.-passwords-are-hard-to-remember&quot;&gt;1. Passwords are hard to remember&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accounts containing sensitive information—Facebook, Dropbox, Amazon, Google, etc.—are difficult to manage when account security and integrity come into play. This is because passwords are inherently unfriendly to the user. Combinations of capital letters, lowercase letters, numerals, and special characters are usually required. Hell, sometimes your password expires three months after you’ve finally memorized it! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explains why so many people use the same passwords across all of their accounts. But fear not my friends! Because there are some smart folks out there making lives easier (assuming your life in modern society isn&amp;rsquo;t already easy enough). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those aforementioned smart folks make standalone apps called password managers. Apps that&amp;rsquo;ll work on both your phone and your computer. There are many different password managers available right now. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keepass.info&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; (Stay tuned for more info on these).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2.-passwords-are-basically-obsolete-anyway&quot;&gt;2. Passwords are basically obsolete anyway&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrong!&lt;/strong&gt; Flying cars are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.terrafugia.com&quot;&gt;real&lt;/a&gt;. But you can&amp;rsquo;t get one just yet. Similarly, passwords will someday be completely replaced by the iris scanner or some other new-fangled-science-fiction-wizardry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a fingerprint reader like Apple&amp;rsquo;s TouchID; it&amp;rsquo;s great for your phone, but passwords are still required for pretty much everything on a desktop computer. And you can&amp;rsquo;t rely on using just your face to login to your favorite Russian mail-order bride service. Not today, anyway. So you best get to learnin&amp;rsquo; about password managers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lastpass&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keepass&quot;&gt;KeePass&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.aejuarez.com/2015/11/09/don-t-pass-up-password-managers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.aejuarez.com/2015/11/09/don-t-pass-up-password-managers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interview the Interviewer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently experienced my first face-to-face interview at a small business in Seattle. No job offer came out of this interview, and that&amp;rsquo;s completely fine. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s great because I learned a lot from the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into the interview expecting to be asked the following types of questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Tell me about yourself?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  What&amp;rsquo;s your greatest weakness?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  How do you speak to an upset customer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I didn&amp;rsquo;t get asked any of these questions. Our interactions were short and, frankly, awkward. I was only asked a couple of simple questions, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t provide very long answers to the questions. On my end, I prepared and asked three questions that only furthered the already minimal amount of dialogue at hand. From this, I have realized that the energy level of others either feeds or saps one&amp;rsquo;s energy, enthusiasm, or authenticity. All of this remains true if I don&amp;rsquo;t work to fight against this tendency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;&amp;quot;to-expect-the-unexpected-shows-a-thoroughly-modern-intellect&amp;quot;-—oscar-wilde&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;To expect the unexpected shows a thoroughly modern intellect&amp;rdquo; —Oscar Wilde&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cliché saying: expect the unexpected, shouldn&amp;rsquo;t go overlooked. I went into the interview expecting to be grilled with questions when in reality I was asked very little. This threw me off. I was most concerned about being well qualified for the job when I should have been focused on showing the interviewer the curious, detailed-oriented person that I am. No matter how qualified a job candidate may be, what is most important for the interviewee is to give the interviewer a sense of his/her personality. The interviewer wants to know how the candidate adds or creates value, and if the candidate is likeable, agreeable, and the correct fit for the work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-body-language-didn&amp;#39;t-show-a-high-level-of-interest&quot;&gt;My body language didn&amp;rsquo;t show a high level of interest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My body language was a little too stiff, a little too much on the reserved side of things. Way back in the spring of 2013, I was introduced to the power of body language by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cwu.edu/it-management/robert-trumpy&quot;&gt;Dr. Bob Trumpy&lt;/a&gt;, professor at CWU. During a business communication course, Dr. Trumpy showed a TED Talk presented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hbs.edu/faculty/Pages/profile.aspx?facId=491042&quot;&gt;Amy Cuddy&lt;/a&gt;, social psychologist and professor at Harvard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/amy_cuddy_your_body_language_shapes_who_you_are?language=en&quot;&gt;immensely popular video&lt;/a&gt;, Amy shares research centered around this deceptively phrased idea: &amp;ldquo;fake it to become it&amp;rdquo;. This statement has nothing to do with being a fraud. The meaning is just the opposite in the sense that posture, hand placement, gestures, and overall disposition creates real, physical, chemical changes in the brain. These changes allow us to become better leaders, followers, team members, or whatever else one might call a righteous hard-working citizen of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all future interactions, I will keep dialogue moving in a meaningful direction—even if the interviewer’s energy is low—and I will not shy away from being my true self. My true self is the confident, inquisitive, always-musing self that will be revealed at my next job interview. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep on power posing, World Wide Web!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.aejuarez.com/2015/03/23/interview-the-interviewer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.aejuarez.com/2015/03/23/interview-the-interviewer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Blog Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogging is all about content. To put simply, Content is King. To put curiously, content is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bee&amp;rsquo;s Knees&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Checkout the disputed origin of this idiom &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phrases.org.uk/meanings/the-bees-knees.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will primarily be focused on writing about tech things; however, I plan to include posts about the many thoughts about life in general that otherwise might escape my memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned, Word Wide Web!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.aejuarez.com/2015/03/11/first-blog-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.aejuarez.com/2015/03/11/first-blog-post/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
